A Finding Aid to the Lloyd Goodrich Papers, 1884-1987, bulk 1927-1987 in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Organization and Committee files, 1933-1982; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 14.5 Linear feet Box 17-31, 37
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1938-1971; 4.2; Archival Resource Key
    Over a period of fifteen years Goodrich served the Association of Art Museum Directors as an advisory director, and on various committees including the Artists-Museums Committee, and the Government and Art Committee. Materials include clippings, correspondence, minutes, reports, and Internal Revenue Service information on art sales.
    - Internal Revenue Service, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 1938-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 13-23)
    - Minutes, 1938-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - Report on Reproduction and Reproduction Rights, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Study in American Art, 1955-1965; 4.3; Archival Resource Key
    Goodrich served on the board of the Carnegie Study, an organization that documented American art and artists. Materials include lists of artworks with accompanying essays, correspondence, information on the Carnegie Corporation, minutes, photographs, and schedules.
    - Architecture, Lists and Essays, 1955-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
    - Barker, Lists and Essays, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Baur, List and Essay, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Carnegie Corporation, General, 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Consultants, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, General, 1958, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Lamar Dodd, 1955-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 11-13)
    - Correspondence, Mrs. Davidson, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Mrs. Pierson, 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, Sandak, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Decorative Arts, Lists and Essays, 1956-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Graphic Arts, Lists and Essays, 1956-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous, Lists and Essays, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Nineteenth Century Painting, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 20-21)
    - Richardson, List & Essay, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Schedules, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Sculpture, Lists and Schedules, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Selected Sets, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Visual Communications, Mildred Constantine, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, 1948-1971; 4.4; Archival Resource Key
    Goodrich served as vice chairman of the National Council on the Arts and Government. Materials include agendas, booklets, by-laws and constitution, clippings, correspondence, proposed and draft legislation, hearings and related testimony, financial records, minutes, notes, press releases, statements, and speeches.
    - General, 1965-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 2-20)
    - American Association of Museums, 1948-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1948-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - American Institute of Architects, 1948-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - American Institute of Decorators, 1950-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Annual Reports, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Art Legislation, Miscellaneous Bills, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Articles, 1948-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Articles, 1948-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 1-5)
    - Artists Equity Association, 1950-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Arts in Society, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Associated Council of the Arts, Ralph Bugard, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1948-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Bill for Federal Advisory Council, General Correspondence, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Business, 1965-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - "Can We Afford to Ignore the Arts?", 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Circulars, Drafts, Bills, 1949-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 13-19)
    - Clippings, 1949-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 20-26)
    - College Art Association, 1948-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Colorado Council on Arts & Humanities, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Commission on Fine Arts, 1950-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 29-30)
    - Committee on Government and Art, Correspondence, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 31-32)
    - Congressional Record Clippings, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Constitution & By-Laws, 1950-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 4-22)
    - Council Members, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Decorative Art in Federal Buildings, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Department of Health, Education & Welfare, 1953-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Description of Various Art Bills, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Editorial Arts, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Executive Committee Luncheon, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Facts & History, Statement of Principles, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Federal Art Legislation, Correspondence, 1956, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Financial, 1962-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 30-35)
    - Fred Thompson, News Releases, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - House Resolutions, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Hearings, 1955-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 1-3)
    - Information Received, 1959-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 4-14)
    - Interim Report, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Legislation, 1953-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 16-20)
    - Letters, 1954-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Liberalize Tariff Laws, 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - List of Commissions and Membership, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - List of Committee Members, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Lists for Statement, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Meetings, 1953-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 26-29)
    - Members, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 30-31)
    - Minutes, 1951-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 32-35)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 36-37)
    - National Academy of Design, 1948-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - National Association of Women Artists, 1950-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - National Collection of Fine Arts, 1967-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities, 1964-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 41-42)
    - National Institute of Arts & Letters, 1951-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - National Sculpture Society, 1954-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - National Society of Mural Painters, 1950-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - News Release on CGA Report, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - 1960s, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Possible Members, Mr. Wagenaar's List, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Press Conference, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Proposed Conference 1961, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Published Material, 1954, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Reports, 1951-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 10-22)
    - Resolution - Government & Art, circa 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - S.3419 Lehman and S.3471, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Sculptor's Guild, 1950-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Site on the Mall, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Smithsonian Gallery, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Speech at American Association of Museums, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Speech at American Federation of Arts, 1951, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Speech at College Art Journal Meeting, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Speech at Yale Symposium, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - State of New York, Assembly No. 6906, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Statement, Federal Advisory Council on the Arts, 1956, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Statement, International Relations Through Cultural Exchanges, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Statement, National Collection of Fine Arts Museum, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Statement, Harold Taylor, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Statement, Lloyd Goodrich at Hearings, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Statement, Lloyd Goodrich Before Subcommittee, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Statement, Submitted to Subcommittee, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Summary of Report to President, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Symposium Art Digest, New School, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Symposium Art Digest, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Talk, New School Symposium, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Talk, WVED Radio, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1964, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Treasurer's Reports & Annual Report, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - "Trends in Government and Art" by Lloyd Goodrich, circa 1948-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 47)
    - Weston, Harold, 1956-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 48)
    - Worden, Article on Grants, 1964-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - Other Organizations and Committees, 1933-1982; 4.5; Archival Resource Key
    Goodrich served on numerous additional associations and committees, including the Artists Equity Association, Artist Tenants Association, New York Attorney General's Advisory Committee on Forgery, Fraud, and as a founding member of the American Art Research Council, among many others. He also advised the Edith Halpert and Sara Roby Foundation Boards. Files contain agendas, booklets and brochures, clippings, correspondence, exhibition lists, congressional legislation, minutes, notes, photographs, and reports.
    There are also materials relating to the American National Exhibition (1959). Along with Henry Hope, Theodore Roszak and Franklin C. Watkins, Goodrich selected the works of sixty-seven American artists for the American National Exhibition (1959) held in Moscow. The Chairman of the House Un-American Activities Committee, Rep. Francis E. Walter claimed that thirty-four of the included artists were affiliated with Communist activities and demanded the removal of those artists. Some of the included artists testified and ultimately, President Eisenhower intervened and allowed for the works to be shown in Moscow.
    - ACLU Censorship Committee, 1956-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 50-51)
    - Albertina Exhibition, Advisory Panel, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 52)
    - American Art Research Council, Documents re Foundation, on Advisory Committee, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    - American Art Research Council, Report, 1943-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - American Art Research Council, Research Data, 1942-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - American Watercolor and Winslow Homer Exhibition, 1944-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 5-6)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto International Exhibition, Selection Committee, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 7-8)
    - Art in America, Editorial Board, 1941-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 9-11)
    - Art Students' League, 1934-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Artist Tenant Association, 1961-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Artist Tenant Association, 1948-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Artists Equity Association, Woodstock Conferences, 1950-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Artists Equity Association, 1970-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 16-17)
    - Artists for CORE, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Bureau of Reclamation Art Program, 1968-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 19-20)
    - Bureau of Reclamation Art Program, Glen Canyon, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Columbia U Seminar 430, 1954-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 22-24)
    - Committee of Religion and Art in America, Member, 1973-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Committee of Selection, American National Exhibition (1959) - Article in Soviet Culture by Kemenov, Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Committee of Selection, American National Exhibition (1959) - Clippings, Duplicates, Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Committee of Selection, American National Exhibition (1959), 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 5-7)
    - Committee of Selection, American National Exhibition (1959) - General Information, Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Committee of Selection, American National Exhibition (1959), 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 9-11)
    - Committee of Selection, American National Exhibition (1959) - Lloyd Goodrich Statement Before Advisory Committee, Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Committee of Selection, American National Exhibition (1959) - USIA Advisory Commission, 1958-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Council of the American Friends of the Tate Gallery, Acquistion Committee, 1958-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - First Biennial of Sao Paulo Museum of Modern Art, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Halpert Foundation, 1970-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 16-19)
    - Halpert Foundation, 1950-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 1-11)
    - John Hay Whitney Foundation Opportunity Fellowships, Jury to Select, 1950-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 12-13)
    - Joint Artists' Museum Committee, 1950-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 14-27)
    - Magazine of Art, 1943-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 1-13)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, Hearn Fund Purchases, Advisor, 1936-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art 100th Anniversary, Nineteenth Century America Advisory Committee, 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Museum of Fine Art, Houston Milestones of American Art Exhibition, Recommendations, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - National Collection of Fine Arts Commission, Acquisitions Committee, 1971-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - New York Attorney General's Advisory Committee on Forgeries, Fraud etc., 1965-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 18-22)
    - New York Attorney General's Advisory Committee on Forgeries, Fraud etc., 1937-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
      Oversized material housed in Box 37, Folder 3-4
    - New York Regional Committee of the Public Works of Art Project, Member, 1933-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Old Westbury Gardens Sculpture Exhibition, Advisory Committee, 1956-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, Lee Hall, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Sara Roby Foundation, 1959-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 6-7)
    - Sculpture in Central Park Exposition, Advisory Committee, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Skowhegan School of Painting & Sculpture, 1946-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 9-11)
    - Smithsonian Art Commission, 1946-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 12-19)
    - Smithsonian Art Commission, 1960-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
    - State Department Art in Embassies Program, 1964-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 4-7)
    - Stone Mountain Memorial Association, 1954-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 8-10)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1930-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 11-24)
    - Oversize New York Attorney General's Advisory Committee on Forgery, Fraud etc., from Box 30, Folder 2, 1937-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
- Exhibition Files, 1944-1986; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 31-32
  There are files for only a few of the many exhibitions curated by Goodrich, all of them on Winslow Homer outside of the Whitney. Materials are scattered but may include correspondence, agreements and financial records, loan records, gallery plans, photographs, and printed materials.
  - Worcester Art Museum, Winslow Homer, 1944-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Wildenstein and Co., Winslow Homer, 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 26-27)
  - National Gallery of Art, Winslow Homer Retrospective, 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - International Arts Guild of the Bahamas, Winslow Homer, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Graphic Art of Winslow Homer, 1968-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 3-5)
  - Farnsworth Museum, Winslow Homer, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Winslow Homer, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Winslow Homer, 1973, 1986; Archival Resource Key; 14 Cassette tapes (Box 32, Folder 8-15)
    Includes some duplicates recorded from originals in 1986
  - Cummer Gallery of Art, Winslow Homer, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 16)
- Printed Material, circa 1920s-1979; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Box 32-33
  Printed materials include clippings, flyers, and exhibition catalogs for speeches or exhibitions organized by Goodrich. Also found are copies of Goodrich's published writings.
  - Clippings and Publicity Materials, Lloyd Goodrich, 1933-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 17-26)
  - Clippings and Publicity Materials, Lloyd Goodrich, 1933-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
  - Clippings and Publicity Materials, General, 1953-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 6-8)
  - Published Writings by Lloyd Goodrich, circa 1920s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
- Scrapbook, 1952-1959; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders Box 33
  There is a dismantled scrapbook of printed material relating to Goodrich's career, spanning the years 1952 to 1959. Materials include clippings, exhibition catalogs and announcements, museum bulletins, and publicity material concerning speeches, exhibitions, and writings by Goodrich.
  - Dismantled Printed Materials Scrapbook, 1952-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
- Photographic Materials, circa 1910-1987; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 3.1 Linear feet Box 33-37
  Scattered photographs are of Lloyd Goodrich, of Goodrich with others, and of travel. Negatives and lantern slides of works of art by Winslow Homer and sixteen x-rays of works of art by Ralph Blakelock are also found. The X-rays are of paintings in teh collection of the Corcoran Gallery, Hirschl & Adler, Whitney Museum, the Worcester Museum, and several private collections.
  Researchers should note that additional photographs of works of art may be found within Series 3.
  - Lloyd Goodrich and Others, circa 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 13)
    Oversized material housed in Box 37
  - Travel, Cruise, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - List of Negatives, circa 1950-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Negatives, Works of Art, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Negatives, Works of Art, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 1-9)
  - Negatives, Works of Art, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 1-3)
  - Lantern Slides, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - X-Rays, Works of Art, circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 36)
  - Oversized Photographs of Lloyd Goodrich and Others, from Box 33, Folder 13, circa 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Oversized List of Negatives, from Box 33, Folder 15, circa 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 2)